Looking for something, Miss?
（マルチネ）
探し物ですか？　お嬢さん
Don't worry. I was just about to leave.
（リタ）
ご心配なく
もう帰るとこだから
Leave? You expect to leave here alive?
（マルチネ）
帰る？　ここから生きたまま？
Don't worry about that, either.
（リタ）
それも ご心配なく
I'm a zombie.
私 ゾンビですから
Oh, so you're already dead?
（マルチネ）
ははあ… あなた 死んでるのね
Then I'll just go ahead and cut you up with these.
なら こいつで
遠慮なく斬り刻めますねえ
I'm waiting for sunrises again
Rise up, rise up, rise up
（アーミラ）
抱き締めれば分かるんだって
（カイザル）ちょっ…
（アーミラ）私が娘だってこと
Let me see the sun
母親は そういうものなんだって
Rage of Bahamut
ねっ ファバ
（ファバロ）
おう ファバも そう思う
Rage of Bahamut
早く会いたいなあ
会えるかなあ
Rage of Bahamut
People always say
"black or white," but the world is so gray
Even angels and demons were once the son of God I praised
temee no gen'in wa temee no naka kara
You're the catalyst for your own demise
zenbu hikurumete omae no saga
It's inherent to your being
kizuku koro ni wa mou you're in a coffin
But by the time you realize, you're in a coffin
It's too late if you want to do something
What the hell is wrong with me?
I can't remember what I wanted to be
Tick, tack, which is what I found
I can see the keys are scattered around
kono yoru ga aketemo nanika kawaru wake ja nee sa
Even though a new day dawns, nothing's gonna change
Yes, I know; yes, I know that I...
I'm the only one
who can save myself
I'll never forget
All I wanna be is me
He said she'll recognize me if I hug her!
He said she'll know I'm her daughter because that's how mothers are!
Right, Fava?
Yeah, I agree.
I can't wait! I hope I get to see her.
Never fear!
心配ありません
このカイザル 必ずや アーミラ嬢の
母上を見つけ出してみせます
I, Kaisar, will find your mother without fail!
And then...
そうすれば…
運命を変えられる
...we can change our fate!
Favaro. You opened our eyes to that option.
ファバロ
それは お前が教えてくれたことだ
教えてくれたことだ！
You opened our eyes to it!
Yeah, I told you about it.
おう ファバが教えたことだ
If you wish to stop Bahamut's revival,
（ドラゴン）
バハムートの復活を止めたくば
鍵の娘を…
take the key girl and kill her.
殺すのだ
Man, gimme a break.
（ファバロ）
勘弁してくれよ たく…
Why me?
なんで俺が…
（民衆）
ジャンヌは無実だ！
Jeanne is innocent!
This must be a mistake!
何かの間違いだ！
ジャンヌ！　ジャンヌ！
Hear me, people of Anatae!
（シャリオス）
アナティの民たちよ！
我らの前にいるのは聖女ではない！
The woman you see is not a saint,
but a messenger of darkness bent on bringing disaster upon this city!
この都に災いをもたらす
闇よりの使者である
こやつは人間を装い
騎士として王都に忍び込み…
She has donned a human guise,
infiltrated the Capital as a knight,
and conspired to commit heinous acts!
（バッカス）
腐れ外道のにおいがするぜ
This stinks of rotten heresy.
Therefore, as king, I hereby
sentence the witch Jeanne d'Arc
（シャリオス）
よって！
王の名において
魔女ジャンヌ･ダルクを
火あぶりの刑に処す！
to be burned alive at the stake!
Stop! Jeanne isn't a witch!
（民衆）
やめろ！
ジャンヌは魔女なんかじゃない
そうだ！　ジャンヌこそ救世主！
Yeah! She's our savior!
In these flames may your sins be atoned;
（修道士）
汝(なんじ)の罪は炎によって償われ
in the name of the Holy Spirit may your soul be cleansed.
汝の魂は…
What are you doing?!
ええい 何をしておる！
魔女をかばう者は 全て反逆者だ
All who defend the witch are traitors!
Quell them at once!
直ちに鎮めよ！
Stop...
（ジャンヌ）
やめてくれ…
Please stop!
やめてくれ
なぜ罪なき民が
傷つかなければならない
Why must the innocent be harmed?
Why do you not protect the people you love?
なぜ愛する者たちを
お護(まも)りくださらない
Why, gods?!
神よ なぜ！
（ガブリエル）
聖なる騎士は神への供物
A Holy Knight is an offering to the gods.
A vessel for the re-manifestation of the Supreme God Zeus.
（ウリエル）
最高神ゼウスを
再び現世させるための依代(よりしろ)
Humans are worthless beings,
good only for serving our purposes.
（ラファエル）
目的の成就を果たせれば
人間など無価値な存在
（ジャンヌ）
違う！　人は神を…
That's not true! People worship the gods!
Jeanne.
（ミカエル）
ジャンヌ
The gods have no love for humans whatsoever.
神は人間など愛してはいないのです
（マルチネ）
立ち向かいなさい 真実に
Now, accept the facts...
and give the people salvation...
そして 救うのです　民たちを
with your own two hands!
あなたの手で
（シャリオス）
邪魔者は消えた
The pest is no more!
S-Stop her! Someone stop that monster!
と… 止めよ！
誰か この化け物を！
The saint went and turned into a witch!
聖女が悪魔になっちまいやがった
（リタ）
今日はシラフなのかしら？
Tell me. Are you sober today?
You...
（バッカス）
てめえは…
There's something I need to ask you.
ちょっと
聞きたいことがあるんだけど
（ファバロ）
よし
There.
（カイザル）
それなら 武器として使えるな
That should make a fine weapon.
にしても
本当に この道で合ってんのか？
Still...
Are you sure we're goin' the right way?
（カイザル）
何を言っている
Don't be silly.
あともう少しで
Lady Amira's mother shouldn't be far from here.
アーミラ嬢の母上が待つ場所に
たどりつくはずだ
ふ～ん…
（アーミラ）ファバ！
（カイザル）ファバロ！
Fava!
Favaro!
Wh-What the hell's going on?!
何なんだよ いきなり！
（カイザル）
なんだ？　ここは…
What is this place?!
The fog...
（ファバロ）
さっきの霧
ネブルビルんときと同じやつか
It's just like back in Nebelville!
（マルチネ）
聞こえますか
Can you hear it?
このすばらしい声が
That splendid voice...
悪魔の鍵が
The Demon Key is screaming to become one with you...
君とひとつになりたいと
叫んでいるのですよ
アーミラ
Amira.
（バッカス）
人間を悪魔に変える魔術だあ？
A spell that turns people into demons?
（リタ）
ジャンヌ･ダルクが
悪魔になったのは そのせいよ
It's what turned Jeanne d'Arc into a demon.
It's possible to obtain magic powers by making a pact with a demon.
悪魔と契約して
魔力を手に入れることはできる
でも…
But...
悪魔そのものになった
なんて話は
I've never heard of anyone transforming into a full-fledged demon before.
聞いたことがないわ
賞金首のひとりに
I've heard rumors of a man with a bounty on his head who possesses such ability.
そういう魔術の使い手がいるって
うわさを聞いたことがある
（リタ）
賞金首？
A bounty?
（バッカス）
ああ 人間か悪魔かすら分からねえ
Yeah. No one's even sure if he's human or demon.
そいつは
異常なまでに死に取りつかれ
They say he has a strange obsession with death.
He can supposedly change
his appearance, control others at will,
顔や姿を自在に変え
他人を自由に操り
屍(しかばね)の山を築き上げてきたんだと
and leaves a mountain of corpses in his wake.
その術が…
And his magic abilities...
...include a demon transformation spell?
人を悪魔に変える魔術ね
It's all just rumor, though.
（バッカス）
まあ あくまでうわさだ
実際に そいつと会ったヤツらは
１人残らず死んでるからな
Not a single person has ever met him and survived, after all.
（リタ）
ちなみに
その賞金首さんの お名前は？
What is his name, anyway?
ああ そいつの名は…
His name is...
（ハンサ）
くわ～
Did we hit something?
何か ひいた？
Watch where you're goin', dumbass!
（バッカス）
気いつけろ！　バカヤロー！
ひいちゃった
Now we've done it.
マルチネ… 先生
Martinet... My teacher...
Why are you here?
なんで ここに？
Teacher?!
（カイザル）
先生？
My teacher told me that I'll meet her
someday as long as I keep this with me.
先生も言ってた
これを持っていれば
いつか必ず会えるって
So this is the guy.
（ファバロ）
こいつか…
I've been waiting for you, Amira.
（マルチネ）
アーミラ
あなたが来るのを待っていましたよ
Here, in Helheim.
この“ヘルヘイム”で
Helheim?
ヘル… ヘイム？
えっ… マジ？
What?! Seriously?!
Impossible!
ありえん！
We were following the compass to Prudisia!
私たちは羅針盤に従い
ブロドシアに向かっていたはず
Prudisia?
ブロドシア？
チッチッチ…
Wrong, wrong, wrong.
違う 違う 違う！
You were on your way here from the very beginning!
あなたたちは最初から
ここに来ることになっていたのです
先生…
What are you talking about, Teacher?
何を言ってるの？
Allow me to introduce you!
（マルチネ）
ご紹介しましょう
This is the gentleman who shall rule the world, now that Demon Lord Satan is gone!
（マルチネ）
魔王サタンなき今…
世界を支配すべきは このお方
Lord Beelzebub, the handsome leader of the demons!
美しき悪魔の盟主
ベルゼビュート様です！
Beelzebub!
（カイザル）
ベルゼ… ビュート
がはっ…
What the hell is this?! I can't move!
なんだ こりゃ！
動けねえ
Amira.
（ベルゼビュート）
アーミラ
It is time to fulfill your purpose...
お前はバハムートの封印を解く道具
and lift Bahamut's seal.
その役目を果たすときだ
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
I've made up my mind!
（アーミラ）
私 決めたの　運命を変えるって
I'm going to change our fate!
I'm going to leave with my mother!
お母さんを連れて帰るって
私の中の鍵を取ってもらうって！
She's going to take the key out of me!
Take it out, huh?
“取ってもらう”ねえ…
Then why not ask her right now?
なら 頼んでみてはどうです？
Your mother.
（マルチネ）
あなたの… お母さんに
ハア… ハア…
Oh, you're alive.
（リタ）
あら 生きてたの
Necromancer!
（アザゼル）
ネクロマンサー
I'm a zombie now.
（リタ）
今はゾンビよ
Don't move.
（バッカス）
動くなよ
何か かまそうとしたら
Try anything funny...
and you're gone for good.
そいつで即 お陀仏(だぶつ)だぜ
What's the meaning of this? Why am I here?
どういうことだ？
なぜ俺は ここにいる？
I have a few questions for you.
（リタ）
あなたに聞きたいことがあるの
（アザゼル）
貴様らと話すことなどない
I have nothing to say to any of you.
（リタ）
鍵の子を使って
It's about whoever is using the key girl for some secret, sinister scheme.
こそこそと悪だくみを
しているヤツらについて…
なんだけど
Mother?
（アーミラ）
お… かあ… さん？
（マルチネ）
さあ お行きなさい
お母さんのもとへ
Go on. Go to your mother.
What's wrong?
どうしました？
I thought you missed her?
ず～っと会いたかったのでしょう？
That angel...
（カイザル）
あの天使が…
She looks just like her.
まんま そっくりじゃねえか
Oh, perhaps you don't believe me?
あっ もしかして疑ってます？
She's the real deal.
本物ですよ
I assure you.
ほ･ん･も･の
Yes, yes. That's it. That's it.
（マルチネ）
そうそう その調子 その調子
Why are these guys playing around like this?
こいつら… なんで
こんな まどろっこしいまねを？
Mother?
（アーミラ）
おかあ… さん？
Is it really you, Mother?!
本当に 本当に お母さんなの？
Please, answer me!
ねえ 答えて
ねえ…
Please!
なんで？
How come?
Why?!
どうして…
どうしました？　アーミラ
What's the matter, Amira?
目の前にいるのは
After all your searching, your mother is finally right in front of you!
あなたが探していた
お母さんですよ
Now, have your mother remove it!
さあ 早く取ってもらいなさい
Your mother who hates you more than anyone in this world!
この世で最も
あなたを憎んでいる母に！
You're lying!
うそだ！
I remember!
私 覚えてる
My mother loved me...
お母さんは 私のこと…
Now do you see?
分かりましたか？
You are an imitation vessel made from this angel.
あなたは その天使を基に作られた
まがい物の器
In fact, you could say that Lord Beelzebub is your true birth parent, Amira.
ベルゼビュート様こそが
アーミラ あなたを生み出した
親と呼ぶべきお方なのですよ
You're lying.
（アーミラ）
うそ…
And that pendant is a device I created to show you false memories.
（マルチネ）
そのペンダントは
私が作った
偽の記憶を見せるための装置
Your memories are nothing more than planted falsehoods.
あなたの記憶は植え付けられた
ただのまがい物にすぎません
You're lying.
（アーミラ）
うそだ…
Though I must admit I never imagined that you would enjoy them this much!
（マルチネ）
でも まさか
そんなに気に入っていただけるとは
思いませんでしたけどね
You're lying! You're lying! You're lying!
うそだ うそだ うそだ うそだ
うそだ！
If you'd like, I can prepare plenty more for you!
まだ お望みならば いくらでも！
用意して差し上げますよ
Fond memories, that is!
お好みの思い出を添えてね
You're lying!
うそだあああ！
You wretches!
（カイザル）
貴様らあ！
Kaisar!
（ファバロ）
カイザル！
You're nothing more than a tool of our making.
（マルチネ）
所詮 あなたは
我らによって作り出された
道具なのです
The Transcendent Key that will revive Bahamut!
バハムートを復活させる
“神魔(しんま)の鍵”としてのね
Transcendent Key...
神魔の鍵…
If I hug her...
（アーミラ）
抱き締めれば…
If I hug her...
抱き締めれば… 分かるんだよね
she'll recognize me, right?
That's how mothers are, right?
母親って
そういうもんなんだよね？
Don't do it.
ダメだ…
Don't do it, Amira!
ダメだ！　アーミラ！
そいつは罠(わな)だ！　行くんじゃねえ！
It's a trap! Stay away!
Amira...
（ニコール）
アーミラ…
Moth—
（アーミラ）
おかあ…
—er...
さん…
Amira!
アーミラ～！
What the hell is that?
なんだ ありゃあ？
（リタ）
まさか！
It can't be!
There's no stopping Bahamut's awakening if things keep going as they are.
（リタ）
このままいくと
バハムートの復活は止められないわ
Tell me what you know. Quickly.
あなたの知ってることを
早く教えなさい
Lowly zombie. Do you honestly hope to save the world?
（アザゼル）
ゾンビ風情が
世界を救いたいとでも
思っているのか？
I don't give a damn about the world.
Those youngsters are my only concern.
（リタ）
世界なんて知らないわ
私が心配なのは あの子たちだけ
I agree with you on the first part.
前半には同感だ
I can't afford to die here, either.
俺も ここで死ぬわけにはいかん
Let's make a deal.
取り引きだ
A deal?
取り引き？
Yes. Take me to Abos.
俺をエイボスへと連れていけ
The Transcendent Key is now complete, Lord.
（マルチネ）
神魔の鍵 完成にてございます
Next is Bahamut.
次はバハムートか
You cretin!
（カイザル）
くそっ アーミラ嬢…
Lady Amira...
Guess there's only one thing left I can do.
（ファバロ）
こうなったら…
残された手段は１つだ
Do you have a plan of some sort?!
（カイザル）
何か… 策があるのか？
Hey!
（ファバロ）おい！
（マルチネ）ん？
俺を…
Let me join you guys!
仲間にしてくれ！
My destiny,
sotto oshiete hoshii
won't you tell me?
aenai
But you're gone
ima wa tooi place to be
in a place so far away
unmei wa kawaru to
"Fate changes"
oshietekureta the truth is free
That's what you told me, and now the truth is free
I miss you
I revere you
You're my everything
I will follow you
subete wa ano toki
It all began then
To the promised land
tsuretette
So take me
yakusoku no basho e
to the promised land
Please! Let me join you guys!
（ファバロ）
頼む！　俺を仲間にしてくれ
Favaro! You cur!
（カイザル）
ファバロ！　貴様！
You would abandon your friends to save your own neck?
仲間を見捨て
自分だけ助かりたいと？
Yeah! These guys were never my friends anyway!
ああ こんなヤツら
はなっから仲間でも何でもねえ
面白い
Amusing.
In that case, drink this.
（マルチネ）
では これを飲むのです
Throwing others off guard and turning the tables on them...
油断させて 一発逆転
I'm very familiar with
your methods, my dear Favaro.
君の手口は よ～く知ってますよ
ファバロ君
あがっ！
A battered Demon?
Crap. We made eye contact!
On the next Rage of Bahamut: Genesis,
"All Roads Lead to Abos."
Run!
Illustration:
Let's Bahamut to the max again next week.